<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mirco Colosi</title>
    <link>https://mircolosi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mirco Colosi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>colosi@diag.uniroma1.it (Mirco Colosi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>colosi@diag.uniroma1.it (Mirco Colosi)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mircolosi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging between Computer and Robot Vision through Data Augmentation: a Case Study on Object Recognition</title>
      <link>https://mircolosi.github.io/pubblications/2017-05-05-object-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>colosi@diag.uniroma1.it (Mirco Colosi)</author>
      <guid>https://mircolosi.github.io/pubblications/2017-05-05-object-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Despite the impressive progress brought by deep network in visual object recognition, robot vision is still far from being a solved problem. The most successful convolutional architectures are developed starting from ImageNet, a large-scale collection of images of object categories downloaded from the Web. This kind of images is very different from the situated and embodied visual experience of robots deployed in unconstrained settings. To reduce the gap between these two visual experiences, this paper proposes a simple yet effective data augmentation layer that zooms on the object of interest and simulates the object detection outcome of a robot vision system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProSLAM: Graph SLAM from a Programmer’s Perspective</title>
      <link>https://mircolosi.github.io/pubblications/2017-09-13-proslam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>colosi@diag.uniroma1.it (Mirco Colosi)</author>
      <guid>https://mircolosi.github.io/pubblications/2017-09-13-proslam/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present ProSLAM, a lightweight stereo visual SLAM system designed with simplicity in mind. Our work stems from the experience gathered by the authors while teaching SLAM to students and aims at providing a highly modular system that can be easily implemented and understood. Rather than focusing on the well known mathematical aspects of Stereo Visual SLAM, in this work we highlight the data structures and the algorithmic aspects that one needs to tackle during the design of such a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://mircolosi.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>colosi@diag.uniroma1.it (Mirco Colosi)</author>
      <guid>https://mircolosi.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Ph.D. Ph.D. Student in Engineering in Computer Science.
During my Ph.D. I am working both at &amp;ldquo;Sapienza” University of Rome and at Robert Bosch Campus, Renningen, B-W, Germany. The main topic of my research is Life-Long SLAM.
My advisor is Prof. Giorgio Grisetti.
June 2018 – December 2018 I moved to Germany and I am working mainly on RGB-D SLAM and Multi-Sensor Calibration
November 2017 – May 2018 I worked on Calibration and 2D SLAM at &amp;ldquo;Sapienza&amp;rdquo; University of Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contacts</title>
      <link>https://mircolosi.github.io/contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>colosi@diag.uniroma1.it (Mirco Colosi)</author>
      <guid>https://mircolosi.github.io/contacts/</guid>
      <description>Lab. Ro.Co.Co., Department of Computer, Control, and Management Engineering (DIAG) “Antonio Ruberti” at Sapienza University of Rome. Via Ariosto, 25. 00185 Rome, Italy.
Contact me at: colosi [at] diag [dot] uniroma1 [dot] it
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://mircolosi.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>colosi@diag.uniroma1.it (Mirco Colosi)</author>
      <guid>https://mircolosi.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Tutor of Laboratorio di Intelligenza e Grafica Interattiva (2017/18) More informations on the course can be found here
 Tutor of Tecniche di Programmazione (2017/18) More informations on the course can be found here
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>